Hi,
大家好
my name is Paul Adenot.
我是 Paul Adenot
I work at Mozilla on anything related to audio and video in
我在 Mozilla
Firefox. 5-p
从事 Firefox 上任何跟音频视频相关的工作 5-p
Today,
今天
I'd like to talk about a recent API called the WebCodecs API.
我希望分享一个最近的 API，名为 WebCodecs API
And in particular about memory access patterns
尤其是跟内存访问模式相关的部分
when using this API in conjunction with other APIs on
在这个 API与其它 API 共同使用
the web platform.
在 Web 平台上执行操作的时候
We'll talk about some raw performance numbers
我们将讨论一些原始的性能数据
when accessing video frames,
当访问视频帧的时候
what WebCodecs does today to minimize memory,
今天什么样的 WebCodecs 可以最小化内存消耗
access overhead
访问开销
and some problems that the API has today,
和这个 API 今天还存在的一些问题
where a solution exists, but hasn't been implemented.
有相关的解决方案，还还没有得到实现
And more importantly about a couple of harder problems that
更重要的是关于几个更困难的问题
we'll tackle in the future,
我们将来要解决
so that using WebCodecs will have the same performance
以便让 WebCodecs 的使用
profile as a native app. 20-p
拥有和 native app 一样的性能特质 20-p
Before starting,
在开始之前
I'd like to say that any simple scenario,
我想说的是，任何简单的场景
such as decoding and rendering video and audio
例如解码、视频渲染和音频渲染
are fairly optimized today,
在今天已经得到相当充分的优化
and we'll be talking about advanced use cases,
我们将讨论一些高级用例
such as big native apps
比如大型原生应用
compiled to WebAssembly that want to leverage WebCodecs
编译为使用 WebCodecs 的 WebAssembly
to speed up their encoding and decoding operations
从而加速他们的编码和解码操作
or other programs
或其它的一些程序
that are making a rather intensive use WebCodecs
在大量使用 WebCodecs 的时候
and want to minimize any inefficiencies. slide-2
并希望最大限度地减少任何低效率操作 slide-2
But first
但首先
let me repeat an old quote
让我重复一句老话
often heard in the free software multimedia development
在自由软件多媒体开发界中
circles:
经常提到的
"memcpy is murder". Behind this tongue-in-cheek sentence
"memcpy 是谋杀". 在这句诙谐的句子背后
lies in important fact: to maximize performance,
是一个重要的事实: 为了最大限度地提高性能
the minimum of memory copies need to happen.
需要最大程度减少内存副本
And the working set of nap needs to be as small as possible
并且这个 App 的工作集需要尽可能地小
to ideally git into CPU caches.
从而理想化地匹配 CPU 缓存
Fetching memory into caches is slow,
将内存提取到缓存中是很慢的
caches are small,
缓存体积很小
so no duplications should happen. slide-3
所以不应该发生重复 slide-3
But first let's consider the size of the problem. 44-p
但首先让我们考虑一下这个体积大小问题 44-p
A video frame in YUV420, full HD, standard dynamic range
YUV420 格式的视频帧，全高清，标准动态范围
is around 4MB.
大约是 4MB
A video frame in YUV420, 4K,
YUV420 格式的视频帧，4K,
standard dynamic range
标准动态范围
is around 16MB.
大约是 16MB
A video frame in P010, full HD, high dynamic range,
P010 格式的视频帧，全高清，高动态范围
(either 10 or 12 bits) is around 32MB. slide-4
（10 位或 12 位）大约为 32MB slide-4
Here are some performance numbers that I've gathered,
以下是我收集的一些性能数据
writing a small C++ program on my extremely high-end
编写一个小的 C++ 程序
Linux workstation,
在我的极高端的 Linux 工作站上
of copying a single frame of this size.
去复制这种大小的一个帧
A video frame in YUV420, full HD,
YUV420 格式的视频帧，全高清
standard dynamic range, takes about 1.5ms to
标准动态范围, 大概需要 1.5ms
copy when the cache is hot,
在热缓存状态时完成复制操作
which means the source is already in the cache.
即资源已经在缓存中的情况
And 4.5ms if not. The source needs to be fetched from memory.
如果不在，则需要 4.5ms。 资源需要从内存中获取
Two frames easily fit in the cache of this CPU. 61-p
两个帧则很容易放进这个 CPU 的缓存中 61-p
A video frame
YUV 420 格式的视频帧，4K，标准动态范围
takes 6.6ms and 17ms when in CPU cache.
在 CPU 缓存的情况则需要6.6ms 和17ms
This only works because the CPU I'm running on
能出现这个效果是因为我跑的 CPU
has lots of cache, and a single frame still fits. 66-p
有非常多的缓存，并且还符合单个视频帧 66-p
A video frame in P010, full HD, high dynamic range
P010 格式的一个视频帧，全高清，高动态范围
either 10 or 12 bits, takes 15ms
10位或者12位的，需要15ms 如果是热缓存
if the caches are hot and 33ms if not.
如果不是则需要33ms
The CPU I'm running this on has 20MB of L3 cache.
这个用例里我跑的 CPU 有20MB的L3缓存
So only a partial frame fits. 71-p
所以只有部分的视频帧适配 71-p
Considering the budget
考虑到预算
for a single frame at 30Hz is 33ms and
对于 30Hz 的单帧是 33ms
16.6ms at 60Hz,
而60Hz 的单帧则是16.6ms
we can quickly see that the numbers here are uncomfortable,
我们很快就可以看出这里的数字并不宜人
and minimizing memory copies are going to be of importance.
将内存副本数量降到最低是很重要的
I'll repeat that standard scenarios in WebCodecs such as
我将重复 WebCodecs 中的标准场景，例如
playback don't make copies.
播放而不生成副本
I'm talking about advanced use cases here,
我在这里要谈论一些高级用例
such as processing. slide-5
比如视频处理 slide-5
Additionally,
另外，
GPU to CPU copies (read back)
GPU 到 CPU 副本 (回读)
and CPU to GPU copies (texture uploads)
和 CPU 到 GPU 副本 (纹理上传)
are also quite expensive.
也是非常昂贵的
It's best to carefully consider when and how they need to be
最好慎重考虑何时以及如何完成它们
and to try to minimize transfers,
并且可能的话尽量减少传输
if possible. WebCodecs has been carefully designed to allow
WebCodecs 经过精心设计，允许
to easily leave VideoFrames on the GPU and makes all copies
轻松地将 VideoFrames 留在 GPU 上并制作所有副本
explicit. slide-6
并将所有副本制作变成显式的 slide-6
But sometimes it's really necessary to perform copies.
但有时确实需要执行副本
Here are three scenarios
下面是
when this is unavoidable. 93-p
三个当这是不可避免的场景 93-p
Custom processing of video frames that
自定义处理
are on the GPU using regular JavaScript or WASM code
在 GPU 上使用常规 JavaScript 或 WASM 代码的视频帧
in which case we need to read back. 96-p
在这种情况下，我们需要回读 96-p
Custom processing of video frames that are on the CPU,
通过 WASM 自定义处理 CPU 上的视频帧
then the data needs to be copied into the WASM heap,
然后需要将数据复制到 WASM 堆中
or working with other web API that requires copies. 100-p
或使用其它需要副本的 Web API 100-p
For example,
例如
playing audio data with an AudioWorklet will require
使用 AudioWorklet 处理音频数据需要
copying into the AudioWorklet output buffer. slide-7
复制到 AudioWorklet 输出缓冲区 slide-7
As said,
正如之前说过
WebCodecs has been designed with
WebCodecs 被设计为
copy minimization in mind.
时刻考虑最少化复制操作
The memory is not visible directly to script,
内存对于脚本是不可见的
and authors need to call a function called "copyTo"
并且作者需要调用一个名为 “copyTo” 的函数
to get an ArrayBuffer that can be directly manipulated.
来获得一个可以直接操作的 ArrayBuffe
This "copyTo" method can also take care of conversion in
这个“copyTo”方法
certain cases.
也可以处理特定的一些用例
when calling clone on a VideoFrame or AudioData object,
当在 VideoFrame 或 AudioData 对象上调用 clone 时
the underlying resources are referenced for a second
底层资源将被第二次引用
instead of copied,
而不是复制
so a single frame can be used in different context
从而可以在不同的上下文中有效地使用单个帧
Doing a deep copy is still possible. 118-p
并且仍然可以进行深度克隆 118-p
Now,
现在，让我们看看今天在 WebCodecs 中存在的一些副本 120-p
First,
首先，解码器的压缩输入 compressed input 当前正被复制
This is not that problematic because the input is a lot
这不会引起问题，因为输入
smaller than the output.
比输出小得多
It could be optimized. 125-p
它可以被优化 125-p
More importantly,
更重要的是
there is currently no way to become the owner of the memory
目前没有办法成为
behind a VideoFrame or an AudioData,
VideoFrame 或 AudioData 背后的内存的拥有者
when it's regular memory,
当它是常规的内存，而非 GPU 的时候 130-p
Finally,
最后
the API
当前的 API 做了大量的分配和释放
thrashing CPU caches unnecessarily. slide-8
不必要地抖动 CPU 缓存 slide-8
Here are two simple design proposals to fix the two last
这里有两个简单的设计方案来解决
points in this list. slide-9
这个清单里的最后两个问题 slide-9
First,
首先
a method called "detach" could return an ArrayBuffer and
一个名为“detach”的方法可以返回一个 ArrayBuffer 和
close the video frame in one call,
在一个调用里关闭视频帧
skipping a copy when possible,
尽可能跳过副本
for example, when it hasn't been cloned,
例如，当它还没有被关闭时
that's fairly common.
这是相当普遍的情况
Similarly, we can add this method on AudioData. slide-10
类似的，我们可以在 AudioData 添加这个方法 slide-10
Next,
接下来
we can limit the native allocation and deallocation pressure by
我们可以通过以下方式来限制 native allocation 和 deallocation 带来的压力
taking a buffer in the decode method, in which the decoded
在 decode 方法中取一个缓冲区，其中 decode 的
data is going to be written to,
数据将被写入
and getting back the input buffer to reuse,
并取回输入缓冲区以
in the output callback.
在输出回调中重新使用
This will matter a lot for audio where it's a lot easier for
这对于音频来说很重要，因为
buffer to fit in CPU caches,
其缓冲区更容易适应 CPU 缓存
but their numbers are a lot bigger. slide-11
但它们的数量要多得多 slide-11
Now let's talk,
现在让我们来谈谈
web platform today. 155-p
今天 Web 平台的一些更棘手的问题 155-p
First,
首先
the necessity to copy from into the WASM heap becomes
从 WASM 堆复制和复制到 WASM 堆的必要性变得
problematic when the data to copy is big enough,
当要复制的数据变得足够大时会出现问题
such as video frames. Decoding into the WASM heap would be
例如对视频帧。 解码到 WASM 堆将是
a welcomed feature, but this needs some work. 160-p
一个受欢迎的功能，但这需要一些努力 160-p
Then there is a problem of passing views over SharedArrayBuffer
然后还有一个通过 SharedArrayBuffer 将视图传递给 API 的问题
SharedArrayBuffer is often a good solution to limit copies,
SharedArrayBuffer 通常是个限制副本的好方法
but it's often unclear what those API do to memory
但通常很难弄清楚这些 API 对内存做了什么
and if they work with concurrent writes to the memory region
以及它们是否
that has been passed to them.
与对传递给它们的内存区域的并发写入一起使用
Having read-only memory ranges on SharedArrayBuffer,
在 SharedArrayBuffer 设定 read-only 范围
could be a solution here,
在这里可能是一个解决方案
but it's a complex problem. 169-p
但这毕竟是一个复杂的问题 169-p
An effort has been started to try to document the problems
在 WICG 已经有一个项目启动开始整理相关问题
about copies on the platform at the WICG,
关于 Web 平台上的内存副本
and I encourage interested parties to voice their
我鼓励感兴趣的各方表达他们的意见
opinions and contribute their experience to the discussion,
并在讨论中分享相关的实践经验
reports from the field are always welcomed and very
非常欢迎来自这个领域的汇报
important to inform future developments. slide-12
这些对于未来的开发是有重要意义的 slide-12
In conclusion,
总而言之
while WebCodecs can and will be improved when it comes
虽然 WebCodecs 在内存访问方面还可以并且将会得到改进
to memory access,
它已经是非常有效的
are already quite fast.
而且性能很好
Making it perfect
让它趋于完美当然是可能的，而且未来将会发生
Thanks.
谢谢